## SORAVITVARANICH

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

https://soravit-varanich.com/ +61-43-447-1253 soravit.var@hotmail.com https://github.com/sarpound

#### PROFILE SUMMARY

As a software engineer with several years of experience in Fintech, I have developed and maintained a financial platform for the front-end team at Refinitiv, an LSEG (London Stock Exchange Group) in Thailand. My key responsibilities included creating new features, bug fixing, and creating unit tests for unexpected behaviour. Additionally, I helped review code for performance, readability, and future use, and validated data requests and responses from the backend team.

## SOFT SKILL

## TECHNICAL SKILL

Fast Learner Typescript Expo Css Git
Adaptability React Js Redux less Exp

Adaptability React Js Redux less Express.js
Teamwork React Native Html Bootstrap Devtools

Accepting feedback Angular Javascript Node Js Firebase (Cloud )

Critical Observation RxJS Service Worker REST API

Problem-solving Respectfulness Collaboration

## EDUCATION

Information technology 2017 - 2021

Sirindhorn International Institute of Technology (SIIT), Thammasat University

**Computer Major** 2014 – 2016

Satit prasarnmit demonstration school (secondary)

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Software Engineer (Front-end team) LSEG (London Stock Exchange Group)

Oct, 2021 - April, 2023

- My primary responsibilities included maintaining and developing a financial platform for clients (Angular 15 and Observable RxJS), specifically focused on implementing a forward exchange rate feature that allows for real-time currency calculations with a web socket.
- Building a server-side application that utilizes service workers to develop localhost on a real domain, which acts as a proxy for the application.
- Developed both client sides to allow the developer to register service workers on their application and the server side (Node JS and Express.js) to serve their application static folder.
- Use knowledge of AWS (Cloud Hosting) to copy their behaviour to my server side and serve static folder to the client side. This approach solves the issues of Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) that all developers in my department in Thailand and other countries often face when connecting to real API domains from localhost, thus enabling seamless testing and development of applications.
- Created a custom element

#### Internship / Web developer

Jun, 2020 - July, 2020

#### Adecco Thailand

- My responsibilities are the maintain and develop Adecco's website.
- I used the .Net framework to develop a website and connect databases with Microsoft SQL.

## **FXForwards (LSEG Project)**

## website:https://soravit-varanich.com/work?projects=fxforwards

Refinitiv, an LSEG (London Stock Exchange Group)

- This application I have developed with Angular 17 and RxJs. For this development purpose, I
  would like to demonstrate the FXForwards application that I looked after when I worked at my
  ex-company. This application is just only focused on the user interface and some features not
  all of them.
- FXForward is a platform in Refinitiv, an LSEG that are derivative contracts that allow participants to exchange currencies at a predetermined rate on a future date, used for hedging or speculating on currency movements.

#### SIIT Gate (Graduated Project)

## website: https://soravit-varanich.web.app/siitgate

Sirindhorn International Institute of Technology (SIIT), Thammasat University

- This application I have developed with React Native and Redux. Additionally, It used Expo CLI.
   This application is my senior project for my last year of university.
- it allows the student to view their lecture notes for each subject.
- it will enable the student to view their grade for each subject.

## **Anti Covid (University Project)**

### website: https://soravit-varanich.web.app/anticovid

Sirindhorn International Institute of Technology (SIIT), Thammasat University

- This application I have developed with React Native and Redux. Additionally, It used Expo CLI.
- This project is a part of ITS432 Mobile Application Programming. When I was in my third year at
  the University. I would like to create a covid-19 application that can help everyone who would
  like to know about the situation of covid-19 in the present. The application will show
  information on covid-19 in real-time.

#### Mercuryt-shirts website

## website: https://mercuryt-shirt.web.app

Freelance

- This website is about a t-shirt store. The website shows a description of the store and shows how can customers order a t-shirt.
- I have used React Js and Material UI to develop